Guide to the Yale Newcomer's Club Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Newcomer's Club records
1937-1987
RU 71
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.25
The records consist of correspondence, notebooks, membership lists, meeting minutes, scrapbooks, and printed matter of the Yale Newcomer's Club.
Yale Newcomer's Club
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, notebooks, membership lists, meeting minutes, scrapbooks, and printed matter of the Yale Newcomer's Club.
College teachers' spouses -- Social networks; College teachers -- Societies, etc.; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Societies, etc.; Yale Newcomer's Club; Yale University Women's Organization; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Societies, etc.
- Records, 1937-1970; Accession 19ND-A-486
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Notebook, 1937-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1943-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitution and standing rules, 1944, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Records, 1937-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Records, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Records and membership lists, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Membership lists, 1952-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Membership eligibility, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Procedures, 1957-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - officers' records, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Officers, 1953-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting: minutes, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1956-1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Programs, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Printed matter: Yale and New Haven Information, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
  - Activity groups (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Yale University Women's Organization and University Council, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Spring Ball, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Records, circa 1969-1987; Accession 1991-A-002
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - Records of the Hospitality Chairperson: includes information about social functions, newsletters, minutes and financial statements:
    - 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
    - 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Brochures, 1975-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Records, 1965-1987; Accession 1991-A-125
  - Correspondence, Reports, Lists
    - 1965 - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1981 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters - Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters - Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Disbursements, 1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Disbursements, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Statements, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cash Receipts, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)